Jakarta, Indonesia, 12410
<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/farisadlinshifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.com/shifair.medium.c

Faris Nur Adlin Experienced Software Engineer (Front End) with 3+ years experience in IT World

(+62) 82250393940

farisnura@gmail.com www.farisadlin.com

ABOUT ME

Faris Nur Adlin is a passionate, experienced front-end developer with 3+ years of experience in web and mobile development and a proven track record of making significant, specific, and self-direction contributions to challenging and complex UX projects. He is proficient with JavaScript, TypeScript, and modern client-side frameworks such as React, Redux, CRA, and Next.js. Seeking a position to apply exceptional problem-solving and collaborative skills as part of a team.

EXPERIENCE

Brick / PT. Brick Teknologi Indonesia

Software Engineer (Front End Web)

September 2023 - May 2024

Jakarta, Indonesia

- Handled the creation and maintenance of innovative features in several online repositories, such as the
 well-known Brick Dashboard (Client Side), BOIVA (Client Side), and Mantul Dashboard (Internal User).
 Advanced technologies including HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, REST API, Styled Component, and
 Material UI Design (Versions 4 and 5) were used to improve important projects like the KPK Project, Brick
 Analytics, and Email Template.
- Implemented JavaScript Obfuscation to randomize the bundle so it cannot be read from the client side (improving security from the client side).
- Implemented AES256-GCM encryption for HTTP requests and responses across several websites, notably the Brick Dashboard (client side) and Mantul Dashboard (internal). This initiative significantly bolstered web security from the client side, setting a new standard in data protection.
- Efficiently led the sunsetting process for various products on the Brick Dashboard, including payroll and BrickFlex (P2P Lending), ensuring a smooth transition and minimal impact on the user experience.
- Introduced and successfully implemented Feature Flag (feature toggle) using Unleash on the Brick Dashboard, marking a first in the application's history. This innovation allowed for more flexible and controlled feature deployment.
- Elevated the code quality by writing extensive unit tests using the Jest and React Testing Libraries.
 Remarkably increased the unit test coverage for Experience, Payment, and Boiva modules from 0% to 80%, significantly improving the reliability and maintainability of the codebase.

Technologies: React, Redux, Redux-Persist, Material-UI (v4 and v5), styled-component, REST API, Github, Figma, React Testing Library, Jest, Vite, and Eslint.

Kargo Technologies / PT. Panthera Biru Indonesia

Software Engineer (Front End Web and Mobile)

May 2022 - September 2023 Jakarta, Indonesia

- Developed and maintained groundbreaking features across multiple repositories on front end web, including NFT (Nexus for Transporter), NFS (Nexus for Shipper), TMS-Admin (Internal), Brokerage Transporter Management System, Webview Transporter, and Armada Web (Internal Tools). Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, GraphQL, Styled-component, Ant Design.
- Developed and maintained mobile apps on front-end mobile including T-App (Transporter App) and D-App (Driver App). Technologies used: Kotlin, Material UI, GraphQL, and Android Studio.
- Enhanced first-mile shipments through the D-App improved operational efficiency for the team by 50%, as many redundant tasks associated with first-mile shipments were streamlined within the D-App and managed directly by the driver.
- Switched from web developer to mobile developer and developed two different features integrated with the back end in only one sprint (two weeks) even though not yet familiar with Kotlin.
- Changed the default sound in the T-App to a custom one and completed the recording process. Then
 deployed the custom sound within T-App. All processes are finished in only a week.
- Successfully refactored and revitalized the invoice feature on NFT only in one sprint and increased web performance on the invoice feature from 5 seconds to 2 seconds.

 Prominent tasks were spearheaded, encompassing the management of invoices, implementation of trial features on NFT, live and historical vehicle tracing for transporters, and the registration of a partnership with Panthera Biru Indonesia (PBI). Consequently, non-PBI transporters were effectively converted into PBI partners and increased from only 3 transporters to 12 transporters. Championed code quality and testing by writing numerous unit tests using Jest and React Testing Library and increased unit test coverage for NFT from 5% to 30%.

Technologies: React, Ant Design, styled-component, GraphQL, Github, Figma, React Testing Library, Android Studio, Jest, Vite, Storybook, and Eslint.

PT. Xapiens Teknologi

February 2021 - April 2022

Software Engineer (Front End Web)

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

- Developed XSwift, a massive managed service product for internal and external clients from scratch as a
 web front-end developer using React and reached user traffic from 0 to more than 300.000 visits in a
 year.
- Consistently achieved sprint goals without any dragging backlog (0 dragging backlog).
- Trusted for deploying web apps regularly in development, staging, hotfix, and production to Rancher.
- Actively participated in sprint review, sprint retrospective, sprint grooming, and sprint planning meetings.
- Thoroughly documented code to ensure easy maintenance and understanding by other developers.
- Wrote several unit tests using Jest. Enzyme, and React Testing Library to ensure product reliability and robustness and increased unit test coverage from 0% to 80%.

Technologies: React, Webpack, Redux, Redux-Persist, React Bootstrap, Kendo, Firebase, REST API, Azure, Adobe XD, React Testing Library, Jest, and Eslint.

PT. Gamatechno Indonesia

December 2019 - June 2020

IT Associate Consultant

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

- Assisted the production team in making the master plan and blueprint such as e-Government.
 Interoperability Framework (e-GIF), SOP ICT. e-Government Masterplan, ICT Masterplan, and Backbone Detail Engineering Design.
- Helped the survey team gather data related to the requirements of the master plan for more than Regional Government
- Held presentations for clients to make the project easily understandable so they could work together much more comfortably with us.
- Assisted the marketing team in preparing the Budget Plan or Rencana Anggaran Belanja (RAB) and also the Terms of Reference or Kerangka Acuan Kerja (KAK) for clients.
- Supported the marketing team in using tools for Email and WhatsApp marketing.
- Helped the division with online marketing when organizing Gamatechno's Online Sharing Session event.

EDUCATION

Universitas Gadjah Mada

January 2017 - October 2019

Master of Engineering (M. Eng); Major in Information Technology

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

- Have a journal published at the International Conference on Electronics Representation and Algorithm (ICERA 2019): Current Trend and Literature on Electronic CM Adoption Review.
- Master Graduate Thesis: Chatbot Implementation in E-Commerce Based on Intent.

Universitas Gadjah Mada

August 2009 - August 2016

Bachelor of Engineering (B. Eng); Major in Electrical Engineering

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Undergraduate Thesis: Effect of Impulse Voltage Front Time on Arrester

PROJECTS

- BEACH RESORT FULLSTACK WEB (https://beachresort-farisadlin.netlify.app)
 Built a beach resort web with sorting based on pricing, guest count, room types, size, breakfast, and pet-friendly features. https://discount.netlify.app)
- WEDDING RISKA FRONT END WEB (https://wedding-riska-website.vercel.app)
 Created a wedding website with a congratulations section for guests to give their congratulations. Utilized: Next.JS, Emotion.JS for CSS (styled-component), Vercel.
- WEDDING RICOPENI FULLSTACK WEB (https://ricopeni.vercel.app)
 Created a wedding website with a congratulations section for guests to give their congratulations. https://discoud.org/ Next.JS, Emotion.JS for CSS (styled-component), Node.JS, MongoDB, Vercel.
- WEDDING EDEL FARIS FULLSTACK WEB (https://wedding-edel-faris-new.vercel.app)
 Created a wedding website with a congratulations section for guests to give their congratulations. Utilized: Next.JS, Emotion.JS for CSS (styled-component), Node.JS, MongoDB, Vercel.
- WEDDING DODE MIRAH FULLSTACK WEB (https://wedding-dode-mirah.vercel.app)
 Made a wedding website that used a unique style like a digital book with animation such as flipping pages. It has a congratulations section so guests that are invited can give congratulations. utilized: Next.JS, Emotion.JS for CSS (styled-component), Node.JS, MongoDB, Vercel.
- VUE POKEMON FRONT END WEB (https://vue-pokemon-page.vercel.app)
 Built a Pokémon page that can catch some Pokémons and can manage your own Pokémon. Utilized: Vue, Pinia, Apollo GraphQL, Vercel.
- FARISADLIN.COM FRONT END WEB (https://www.farisadlin.com)
 Built and deployed a single-page personal portfolio website. Utilized: Next.JS, Three.JS, React Three Fiber, Tailwind, Vercel.